Joseph Kihara Njoroge

Software Developer

Experienced software engineer with a passion for developing innovative programs that expedite the efficiency and effectiveness of organizational success. Well-versed in technology and writing code to create systems that are reliable and user-friendly. Confident communicator, strategic thinker, and innovative creator to develop software that is customized to meet a company's or organization's needs, highlight their core competencies, and further their success.

Work History

2021-08 -2022-02

Software Engineer

Machini Technologies, Nairobi, Nairobi

- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Collaborated on stages of systems development lifecycle from requirement gathering to production releases.
- Designed and maintained streamlined, reusable and reliable code for use within distributed cloud environments.
- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality.

2021-03 -2021-06

Software Developer Trainee

Skaehub Technologies, Nairobi

- Collaborated effectively with members of software development team and personnel in other departments.
- Created interactive websites with software development department using Python and Javascript frameworks.
- Wrote clean, clear and well-tested code for various

Contact

Address

Nairobi, Central

Phone

079 855 6797

E-mail

kiharajoseph72@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kihara-njoroge-9367251

Skills

Python Programming Skills

JavaScript

Diango

ReactJS

API Development

HTML and CSS

SQL

Linux

Postgresql

Git

Testing

projects.

- Partnered with company mentor to learn best practices in software design.
- Added permissions-based capabilities to existing IT dashboard.
- Prepared and submitted reports and other documentation to assist development team members.

Education

2017-09 -Current

Bachelor of Science: Industrial Mathematics

JKUAT - Juja

Referees

1.Alfred Mancini

Machini Technologies LTD CEO Cell:0727750007

2.Ebo Mutele

SKaehub Technologies Lead Developer Cell:070798419